* _description_ Privacy Policy
    ============================

ServiceArizona Privacy Policy
-----------------------------

[Information Collected through our "User Survey" and "Contact Us" feature](#5survey)[Security](#6security)  

Thank you for visiting ServiceArizona and reviewing our Privacy Policy. This policy is designed to inform our customers about the services that are available through ServiceArizona, how certain information may be collected and/or used as a result of you visiting our web site or requesting services online, and what steps we are taking to ensure the security of customer data.

Your rights to privacy are of utmost importance to the Arizona Department of Transportation/Motor Vehicle Division (MVD) and its partner, IBM Corp. It is our desire to earn your trust and confidence when you conduct business with us via the Internet.

Online Customer Service and Alternatives
----------------------------------------

ServiceArizona offers many of the services online that you might otherwise transact in person with MVD. Our goal is to provide citizens with a more convenient and efficient means in which to interact with Arizona Government. If at any time you choose not to proceed with a transaction offered through the ServiceArizona web site, your choice will in no way affect your ability to receive services. If you prefer to apply for services in person, you may do so at one of MVD's field offices or Authorized Third Party Provider locations. [Nearest MVD Office and Authorized Third Party provider.](https://servicearizona.com/links/hours)

Collection and Use of Information
---------------------------------

ServiceArizona utilizes session "cookies" (small bits of data that a web server stores on your computer's hard drive) to collect certain information about your visit to this web site. These session cookie(s) are used to maintain your transaction(s) on ServiceArizona and expire at the end of the session. This information never identifies you personally and consists of only the following items:

1. Which ServiceArizona application you have used; and
2. The date and time of your access.

None of the above information is shared, sold, or otherwise disseminated by ServiceArizona. Again, we do not automatically record any information about you as an individual.

Please be aware that if your Internet browser is configured to refuse or disable "cookies," your ability to view our web pages will be unaffected, but you will not be able to take advantage of any of our online services and will instead have to transact business with MVD either in person or by mail.

Google Analytics
----------------

ServiceArizona uses a tool called "Google Analytics" to collect information about use of this site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve this site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google's ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html). You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by disabling cookies on your browser.

Google Adwords
--------------

ServiceArizona uses Google AdWords, which uses a conversion tracking cookie (also called a "conversion pixel") whenever you click on a ServiceArizona ad delivered by Google. These cookies become ineffective after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. If you visit specific pages of our website, Google and ServiceArizona can track whether you were forwarded to that page by clicking on one of our ads.

Data obtained through use of conversion cookies are used for statistical reporting only: these statistics tell us the total number of users who clicked on the ad delivered by Google and opened a webpage having a conversion tracking tag. We do not however receive any information allowing personal identification of users from Google. We are unable to cross-reference the data obtained to any specific user.

Information about how to opt out of Google Adwords can be found on the Google Ads Settings web page.

Advertisement Remarketing/Retargeting
-------------------------------------

ServiceArizona does not use Google Remarketing.

Facebook Ads Conversion Tracking
--------------------------------

ServiceArizona uses a tool called "Facebook Ads Conversion Tracking" or "Facebook Tracking Pixel" to collect information about use of this site. Facebook Ads Conversion Tracking collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information we get from Facebook Ads Conversion Tracking only to improve this site. Facebook Ads Conversion Tracking collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Facebook Ads Conversion Tracking with personally identifiable information.

Information You Choose to Provide
---------------------------------

When applying for services through ServiceArizona, you will be required to enter certain personal information, such as your name, home address, birth date, driver's license or identification card number, and credit card number. For each online transaction, we ask for no more than the information required to process that transaction. The questions posed are similar to those you would be asked during an in-person visit to an MVD office or through the mail. Only those MVD and IBM employees who need your information in order to provide the services offered on this web site are given access to such information.

Please be assured that the personal information you disclose to us online will be held in the strictest confidence while ServiceArizona processes your transaction and will not be shared, sold, or otherwise disseminated to any outside person or entity, except as required or authorized by law. With only limited exceptions, the privacy of your personal information is protected by the Federal Driver's Privacy Protection Act 18 U.S.C 2721-2725, as well as Title 28, Chapter 2, Article 5 of the Arizona Revised Statutes and, unless you specifically give us your consent by checking the consent box which appears on our online service applications before a transaction can be completed, we are not permitted to provide or disclose such information to unauthorized persons or entities.

However, because some of the information submitted to MVD (either through ServiceArizona or directly) is potentially subject to release under Arizona's Public Records Law, the agency may be required to divulge certain information in response to a lawful public records request or in response to a warrant, subpoena, or other court order. When necessary, we may also disclose personal information to law enforcement officials if there is reason to believe that the disclosure of such information is required to identify, contact, or bring legal action against an individual who attempts to perpetrate a fraud against, or gain unauthorized access to the ServiceArizona web site.

Information Collected through our "User Survey" and "Contact Us" feature
------------------------------------------------------------------------

In order to improve our services, we ask that you take a moment to give us feedback through our "User Survey." The survey is anonymous. Information collected through the survey is used solely to evaluate the ease of use of this site and to determine possible future enhancements.

If you elect to use ServiceArizona's "Contact Us" feature, an email address will be required in order for us to respond to your inquiries. We maintain the privacy of any personally identifiable information, such as your email address received through the "Contact Us" feature to the same extent as otherwise described in this policy.

Security 
---------

We have taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of our computer systems and networks, as well as the confidentiality of the information transmitted to us from individual users. Please refer to the "What about security?" section of our information page for further details regarding the security mechanisms utilized by ServiceArizona.

External Links Disclaimer
-------------------------

ServiceArizona contains links to various other web sites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on ServiceArizona and this Privacy Policy will not apply, because you are then subject to the privacy policy of that new site. Links to web sites outside of State government are offered solely for your convenience. The State of Arizona is not responsible for and has no control over the policies or content of any third-party sites.

This Privacy Policy Is Subject To Change
----------------------------------------

ServiceArizona's Privacy Policy may be updated or revised from time to time, so please check back with us periodically in order to receive advance notice of any substantive changes to the manner in which the information you disclose on this web site may be collected, used, or disseminated.

Neither the State of Arizona, nor any State agency, officer, employee, or contractor warrants the accuracy, reliability, or timeliness of the information contained on the ServiceArizona web site, portions of which may be inaccurate or outdated. Any person or entity that relies on such information does so at his or her own risk.

Contact Information
-------------------

If you have any questions about the information presented in this Privacy Policy, use our [online contact form](https://apps.azdot.gov/contact_adot/).

4.1.3
